<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio of Mushfiqur Rahman on Mushfiqur Rahman</title>
    <link>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio of Mushfiqur Rahman on Mushfiqur Rahman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 09:20:42 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 09:20:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>NLP has been a little difficult for me to grasp ever since I started investing my time in AI. I always kinda felt hard to get into NLP topics. After successfully completing several Computer Vision tasks, I thought it is high time to focus on Natural Language Processing. I learned some concepts of NLP from my Deep learning specialization by Andrew Ng. Unfortunately, I almost forgot most of the concepts. So this project was extremely helpful for me to get back on track again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depression and Happiness Factor Analysis</title>
      <link>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 10:27:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>I had the experience to implement several machine learning algorithms, and also gained an understanding of how ML algorithms work. This course also taught us how a basic artificial neural network works. The dataset we used for this course comprises of the individual data about our mental health. The data ranges from our first to fourth year. It has many features like: &amp;lsquo;Which year are you in?&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;How are you feeling right now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coverage Checker</title>
      <link>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 06:27:42 -1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>This application is based on a CatBoost machine learning model. This basically takes four queries from the user (Upazila/Thana name, Network availability (3G/4G), District, and Zip code) and outputs the best operator for that location. his model was trained on the data I collected from the Opensingnal application. I collected 22,360 data for 559 locations in Bangladesh. Currently, this model is based on a static dataset but in the future, I have a plan to upgrade it to a real-time data collection-based model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis (Retail)</title>
      <link>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This project illustrates the reason behind sales of each items. We get a clear view of which category items are more popular in which region. We also get the idea which cities do most of the business and where the most profit and loss are. We get clear idea of items and categories which profits most or loss most. A item from a category can make profit where other items can conduct loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-care Chatbot</title>
      <link>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>A simple chatbot using the WHO given COVID-19 FAQ dataset and a .json file. I tried to implement this bot using Natural Language Processing. The dataset was collected from the WHO website. This chatbot uses stemming for tokenizing the words. A deep neural network was used for training the model. The model achieved 96.65% accuracy. The model has been saved for future use. This model is able to provide answers if a keyword related to COVID-19 is provided as an input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face Recognition of Football Players.</title>
      <link>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mushfiqur-Rahman-Robin.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This was a practice project of Face Recognition where I tried to recognize football players from their images. A pre-trained InceptionV3 model was used for the classification task. The final layer of the Inception model was replaced by a flatten layer, a dense layer with 1024 hidden units, and a dropout layer. As the dataset contains five football player classes, the output layer had 5 hidden units with a softmax activation function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
